Rory Harder

AOS Philosophy of Language, Philosophy of Mind AOC Epistemology (including formal), Logic

Academic Employment

2021–2022 Postdoctoral Fellow, University of Toronto 2019–2021 Part Time Lecturer, Rutgers University

Education

GRADUATE

2015–2022 PHD in Philosophy, University of Toronto, ABD

Dissertation Title: Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Co-Supervisors: Imogen Dickie and Nate Charlow

Scheduled Defense: March 28, 2022

VISITING STUDENT in Linguistics, Rutgers University

Host Supervisor: Simon Charlow

Undergraduate

2012–2015 BA (Hons) with High Distinction in Philosophy (Specialist) and History and Philosophy

of Science and Technology (Minor), University of Toronto

2011–2012 Trent University 2010–2011 Fleming College

Papers

PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL ARTICLES

Accepted Joint Attention and Communication

Inquiry: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Philosophy

In Progress

[A paper on the formal semantics of demonstratives]

Revise and Resubmit

[A paper on demonstratives and joint attention]

Under Review

Clearing up Clouds: Underspecification in Demonstrative Communication *In Preparation*

Presentations

Joint Attention: The Window Into Other Minds?

American Philosophical Association (APA) Pacific Division Meeting (Symposium)

Joint Attention and Communication

Mutual Knowledge 40 Workshop
A Puzzle About Demonstrative Understanding

PhiLang 2021

2020 Perspectives in Demonstrative Semantics

WeSSLLI Student Session; Szklarska Poreba Workshop

The Affiliative Conception of Sense

Communication, Context, Conversation Workshop

Clearing up Clouds

APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium)

2018 Clearing up Clouds

Context, Cognition, and Communication Conference

2017 Inferences and Neutrality of the Deliberative Ought

APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium); Canadian Philosophical Association Meeting

Invited

2020 The Grammar of Reference

New York Philosophy of Language Workshop

2017 Inferences and Neutrality of the Deliberative Ought

Semantics Research Group (University of Toronto Department of Linguistics); Computational Linguistics Seminar (University of Toronto Department of Computer Science)

Teaching

Course Instructorships at Rutgers University

Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year, Online)

Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year)

Course Instructorships at the University of Toronto

Special Topics in Philosophy: Frege's Puzzle (3rd year, Online)

Issues in Philosophy of Mind: Perception and Conception (3rd year)

Rory Harder 2

OTHER

Super-TA for the Socrates Project (Supervising Undergraduate TAs, University of Toronto)
Philosophy Don (Tutor and Residence Assistant, Trinity College, University of Toronto)

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIPS AT THE UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Ancient Philosophy (2nd year), 17th- and 18th-Century Philosophy (2nd year), Introduction to Philosophy (1st year), Knowledge and Reality (2nd year), Probability and Inductive Logic (2nd year), Introduction to Symbolic Logic (2nd year, online)

Scholarships & Awards

GRADUATE

2020–2021 Doctoral Completion Award (\$14,859)

Merit-based award for graduate students at the University of Toronto.

2019–2020 Ontario Graduate Scholarship (\$15,000)

Merit-based scholarship for graduate students at public universities in Ontario.

SSHRC CGS Michael Smith Foreign Study Supplement (\$6,000)

Awarded annually to 125 Canadian graduate students in the social sciences and humanities.

2016–2019 SSHRC Joseph-Armand Bombardier CGS Doctoral Scholarship (\$105,000)

Awarded to about 22% of applicants, who are Canadian graduate students in the social sciences and humanities.

Undergraduate

2012

2017

The George Kennedy Scholarship, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto Awarded annually to a graduating philosophy student.

Socrates Award, Department of Philosophy, Trent University

Awarded annually to a philosophy student in each of the second and third years.

Professional Activity

GRADUATE STUDENT COORDINATOR for Institutional Strategic Initiative in Language and Cognition, University of Toronto

STUDENT PARTICIPANT at 29th European Summer School in Logic, Language, and Information

STUDENT PARTICIPANT at Seventh North American Summer School on Logic, Language, and Information

Referee and Commentater for Philosophy Graduate Student Conference, University of Toronto

Rory Harder

Graduate Coursework

History Seminar in Plato; Consciousness Then and Now

Ethics Controlling Attitudes; Valuing, Narrative, and What Matters in Life

LEMM Perception and Epistemology; Vagueness; Mind or World; Semantics for Philosophy; For-

mal Epistemology; Metasemantics; Frege; Deductive and Inductive Logic

Linguistics Topics in Event Semantics; Introduction to Syntactic Theory

Dissertation

Title Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Summary

My dissertation develops a view of human communication according to which it is the joint activity of making sense of one another, as fellow agents, in virtue of our actions. I consider the relationship between communication and joint attention in order to show how my view provides a superior successor to orthodox Griceanism. I also motivate my view by using it to explain how there can be successful communication, involving a demonstrative, despite the interlocutors not settling on one or another object as referent. Finally, I address a challenge, which arises for any Gricean view of communication, of explaining what is special about linguistic communication. My answer is based on a formal semantics for demonstratives and related expressions, and draws upon the tradition of dynamic semantics.

References

Research IMOGEN DICKIE, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: imogen.dickie@utoronto.ca

NATE CHARLOW, Associate Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: nate.charlow@utoronto.ca

PHILIP KREMER, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: philip.kremer@utoronto.ca

Teaching RACHEL BARNEY, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: rachel.barney@utoronto.ca

Contact Information

E-mail rory.harder@mail.utoronto.ca https://www.roryharder.com

Address Philosophy Department, 170 St. George St., Toronto, ON, Canada M5R 2M8

Rory Harder 4